# **Diego Thon Cortés**

# Front-End Developer

#### CONTACT

+ (56) 9 84137867.

Diego.thon.c@gmail.com.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript

Angular

ReactJS (Beginner)

Firebase (Beginner)

**SCSS** 

**Bootstrap** 

**Angular Material** 

Tailwind (Beginner)

Git

Spanish (Native)

English (C1 Advanced)

#### CERTIFICATIONS

**EF Standard English Test (EF SET)** 

#### **ABOUT ME**

Software engineer, with 2 years and 9 months of experience in programming languages, tools and frameworks.

I'm currently working as a semi-senior programmer.

My experience includes Front-end development in web platform, using Scrum methodology.

About my skills I can remark the pro-activity, self-taught and very much wanting to learn new things within the IT area and the software development.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Front-End Developer (Soho)

6/2022 - Current

- Redesign of graphic interface for web platform proposed by the User (Gasco, Zurich,
- Usage of external API's to create online payment using providers such as Webpay and Zumpago.
- Keeping clean and documented code with low quantity of bugs in case of future changes and improvements.
- Used Flexbox and @Media only screen for responsiveness and adaptability before different viewports.
- Framework used: Angular 11+.
- Management of Jira and Kanban board for the tasks states and Confluence for documentation.
- Used Bitbucket for repositories.

## Front-End Developer (Everis NTT DATA)

1/2021 - 6/2022

- Update and re-design of graphic interface on applications proposed by the user (LATAM Airlines - Alemana Clinic).
- Updating and creating new services and Http gueries for the usage of APIs.
- Keep clean and updated code for future changes.
- Using HTML, CSS and Bootstrap for various projects.
- Creation of the full DispoOnline Front-end Latam Project.
- Framework: Angular 8+.
- Management of Jira Kanban board for the detail of tasks.
- Management of BitBucket and GitLab repositories.

## **Software engineering (Pozo Almonte Municipal Corporation)**

5/2019 - 12/2019

- Making of Web Application, focused in the sale of graveyard lands in Pozo Almonte.
- Programming language used for Backend C# .NET.
- Programming language used for Front-end Angular 7.
- Database Sql Server 2014.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Inacap Valdivia, Chile (University)

Computer engineering, 2012 - 2018

2019 - Graduated

2019 - Licensed